Guide to the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Architectural Records, 1883-1888 AIS.1980.20
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Architectural Records
1883-1888
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Richardson, H. H. (Henry Hobson), 1838-1886
Ord, John
Myers, Elijah E.
Boyington, William W.
AIS.1980.20
186 items (24 flat file folders)
Presentation drawings and plans by Henry Hobson Richardson, William W. Boyington, Elijah E. Meyers, and John Ord were submitted for the 1883 Allegheny County courthouse and jail architectural competition. H.H. Richardson's design was chosen in 1884, and construction took place between 1884 and 1888. This collection includes the presentation drawings of all four architects, as well as working drawings by Richardson that were used in the construction of the project.
History
In 1883, the Allegheny County commissioners invited 100 architects to participate in competition for a new courthouse design to replace the courthouse on the same site that was destroyed by fire in 1882. The finalists, William W. Boyington (1818-1898), Elijah E. Meyers (1832-1909), John Ord (1871-1910), and Henry Hobson Richardson (1838-1886), were offered $2,500 each to prepare studies. Boyington was one of Chicago's first architects. Meyers, based in Detroit, was a successful designer of government buildings. Ord, who lived in Philadelphia, was part of the architecture team responsible for Philadelphia City Hall. However, it was Richardson's design that attracted the attention of the commissioners with its simplicity and the clarity of its planning, and was chosen as the winner in 1884.
The city of Pittsburgh requested that the jail be constructed before the courthouse, and construction on the jail began in 1884. The jail is enclosed by a stone wall with towers. Although Richardson witnessed the completion of the jail, he died April 27, 1886, two years before the courthouse was completed. He chose three men who worked in his office to continue his practice: George Foster Shepley (1858-1903), Charles Hercules Rutan (1851-1914), and Charles Allerton Coolidge (1858-1936). They changed the name of the firm to Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge, and completed the Pittsburgh project. Another person who played an important role in the project was Orlando Whitney Norcross (1839-1920), the leading partner in Norcross Brothers, general contractors located in Massachusetts. Richardson relied on Norcross for his knowledge of materials and construction techniques. Allegheny County awarded the construction contract to Norcross Brothers on September 1, 1884, and they completed the project according to Richardson's plans. The courthouse was dedicated on September 24, 1888. William M. Darlington, the oldest living member of the Allegheny Bar Association, accepted the ceremonial keys to the courthouse.
Richardson considered the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail one of his finest works. By 1878, he had achieved a personal approach to design, and by 1882 he was recognized as the leading architect in America. The Allegheny County Courthouse features Richardson's signature details, the columns, arches, and ornament that came to be associated with the "Richardson Romanesque" style. The design quickly influenced building styles around the country as local government building of a similar style were soon constructed. Along with Richardson's Trinity Church in Boston, the Allegheny County Courthouse was one of the most widely copied of architectural forms in the late-nineteenth century United States. Modern architectural historians regard the jail highly for its plain outline, functional appropriateness, and almost complete lack of historically derived detail.
Richardson's Allegheny County courthouse and jail still stand as outstanding examples of Pittsburgh's architectural masterpieces.
Scope and Content Notes
Series I includes drawings submitted by four architects to the competition for the design of Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail. The presentation drawings of H.H. Richardson (6 items), William W. Boyington (17 items), Elijah E. Myers (19 items), and John Ord (15 items) are predominately on paper, though a few are on linen. These materials are dated 1883.
Series II includes drawings from Richardson's firm, the majority of which are black ink on linen with color wash. These plans document Richardson's original design for the courthouse and jail, as it was built, between 1884 and 1888. The design method used in Richardson's office followed his experience working in Paris, in which Richardson would give small sketches to his draftsmen to be developed into final drawings. Richardson signed fifty-six of the drawings, and many are stamped "Office of H.H. Richardson, Pittsburgh, PA." The bulk of these drawings are dated 1883-1884.
Series III includes blueprints of additions and alterations made to the courthouse and jail after it was erected.
Arrangement
Series I. Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Competition Presentation Drawings
Series II. Richardson's working plans for the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail
Series III. Alterations and Additions to Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail
Access Restrictions
No restrictions, but please make an appointment to arrange access.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by County of Allegheny, Pa., in September 1979.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
In 2005-2006, the University Library System's Preservation Department encapsulated these large drawings in mylar to help protect their fragile nature, and, except for eight oversized items, created housing for them in specially constructed folders.
Custodial History
In 1977, the Pittsburgh Chapter of the American Institute of Architects (AIA) sponsored an exhibition in the Courthouse titled: "Henry Hobson Richardson: Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail." Drawings by all four original competing firms were found in various locations throughout the City-County Buildings and the Courthouse. AIA volunteers encouraged the County employees to gather all the drawings in one place. From this collection, twenty-three examples were chosen for exhibition and photocopied for display, and the originals were returned to storage.
Because the Courthouse storage facilities were not climate controlled, Ann Bayard Ketterer, an architect and member of AIA, worked with the county to find an archival facility to house the collection. The Archives of Industrial Society at the University of Pittsburgh was selected and the collection was deposited by the County of Allegheny, September 1979, by an agreement dated May 23, 1979.
Ms. Ketterer headed AIA's Richardson Restoration Committee, which provided funding for a large five-drawer plan file to house the drawings in Hillman Library at the University of Pittsburgh. She organized the materials and completed an inventory.
The drawings were moved with the rest of the Archives in 2002 to its present location in Point Breeze.
Previous Citation
Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Architectural Records, 1883-1948, AIS.1980.20, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Harvard University's Houghton Library holds an H.H. Richardson archival collection that includes a total of 267 drawings of the design for the courthouse, as well as 63 drawings showing the design for the jail portion of the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail. All drawings have been microfilmed. For a complete catalog listing, visit http://lms01.harvard.edu/ and search the terms "richardson allegheny county courthouse."
Official Report of the Dedicatory Exercises Held at the New Court House at the City of Pittsburgh, County of Allegheny, on Monday, September 24, A.D. 1888. Pittsburgh: Wm. G. Johnston & Co., 1889.
https://digital.library.pitt.edu/islandora/object/pitt%3A31735038308866
Separated Material
Eight oversized items bearing County numbers 779 -- 781; 788 -- 789; 7926; 7929 -- 7930 are stored separately in folder 22 (located on top of flatfile 4) and have not been encapsulated.
Architecture; Courthouses -- Pennsylvania; City halls -- Pennsylvania; Jails -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Architectural drawings (Visual works); Architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Architecture -- Competitions; Prisons -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; County government -- Pennsylvania; Architecture -- Pennsylvania; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Prisons -- Pennsylvania; Public works -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Drawings (Visual works); Government; Boyington, William W.; Myers, Elijah E.; Norcross Brothers, General Contractors; Ord, John; Richardson, H. H. (Henry Hobson), 1838-1886
- Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Competition Presentation Drawings, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains presentation drawings, which are of the courthouse and jail as imagined by the architects who competed for the project. Included are concept drawings by H.H. Richardson, William W. Boyington, Elijah E. Myers, and John Ord.
  - Grant Street Elevation, 7900 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 4)
    Missing Title
    County Number: 7900
    Architect: W.W. Boyington
    Description: Courthouse and Jail perspective, Courthouse presentation drawing
    Scale: Not Available
    Media: Sepia ink on stiff paper, blue wash
    Size: 41 x 32 1/2
    Stamped: Not Available
    Signed: signature ripped off, (taped -- left bottom corner)
    Architect's No.: Not Available
    Condition: Good, corners are torn off
  - Front Elevation on Grant Street, 7901 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 5)
    County Number: 7901
    Description: Courthouse presentation drawing
    Scale: 1/8"
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper
    Size: 35 x 50
    Signed: Not Available
    Condition: Fair, torn
  - Side Elevation on Diamond Street and Fifth Avenue, 7902 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 6)
    County Number: 7902
    Size: 36 1/2 x 47 3/4
    Condition: Poor, torn, (large section missing from top right)
  - Longitudinal Section on Line C-D, 7903 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 7)
    County Number: 7903
    Size: 39 x 47 3/4
    Condition: Good, missing large sections on corners
  - Transverse Section on Line A-B, 7904 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 8)
    County Number: 7904
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red ink
    Condition: Fair, contains hole, (floating flakes of paper in encapsulation)
  - Plan of Basement, 7905 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 1)
    County Number: 7905
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red and blue ink
    Size: 47 x 50
    Condition: Good
  - Plan of Main or First Floor, 7906 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 2)
    County Number: 7906
    Condition: Fair
  - Plan of Second Floor, 7907 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 3)
    County Number: 7907
    Condition: Fair, small hole, (tears, loose chips)
  - Plan of Third Floor, 7908 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 4)
    County Number: 7908
    Condition: Good, (torn edges)
  - Details of Trusses & Girders for Courthouse & Jail, 7909 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 5)
    County Number: 7909
    Description: Courthouse & Jail presentation drawing
    Scale: 1/4"
    Size: 49 1/2 x 23 1/4
    Condition: Fair, (torn right side)
  - Detail of Main Entrance, 7910 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 6)
    County Number: 7910
    Scale: 1/2"
    Media: Black ink on paper, color wash
    Size: 39 3/4 x 22 1/2
    Signed: W.W. Boyington, Archt.
    Condition: Good, (corners torn)
  - Detail of Bay Side, 7911 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 7)
    County Number: 7911
    Media: Pencil on paper, color wash
    Size: 38 1/2 x 20 1/4
    Condition: Good, (torn corners)
  - Supreme Court, 7912 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 8)
    County Number: 7912
    Description: Courthouse presentation rendering, interior of Supreme Court
    Size: 24 1/4 x 21 1/4
    Signed: W.W. Boyington, Archt., Supreme Court
  - Section of Lines CD/AB, 7913 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 16, Item 9)
    County Number: 7913
    Description: Jail presentation drawing
    Media: Black ink on paper
    Size: 33 3/4 x 43 1/2
    Condition: Fair, (Fragile, tears, taped)
  - Basement Plan of Jail, 7914 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 1)
    County Number: 7914
    Media: Black ink on paper, red & blue wash
    Size: 44 x 35
  - First Floor Plan of Jail, 7915 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 2)
    County Number: 7915
    Media: Black ink on paper, blue wash
    Size: 43 1/2 x 31
  - Second Floor Plan, 7916 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 3)
    County Number: 7916
    Size: 45 x 31
  - Sub-Basement Plan Showing Thickness of Walls, 7917 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 4)
    County Number: 7917
    Architect: E.E. Myers
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue & red ink
    Size: 45 x 37 1/2
    Stamped: E.E. Myers Architect, Detroit, Mich.
    Architect's No.: 1
  - First Story Plan, 7919 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 5)
    County Number: 7919
    Description: Courthouse presentation drawing, full-color rendering
    Media: Black ink on paper, six or more colors applied
    Size: 35 1/4 x 44 1/2
    Architect's No.: 3
  - Second Story Plan, 7920 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 6)
    County Number: 7920
    Media: Black ink on paper, colors applied
    Size: 43 3/4 x 33 3/4
    Architect's No.: 4
  - Third Story Plan, 7921 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 7)
    County Number: 7921
    Size: 34 3/4 x 43 3/4
    Architect's No.: 5
    Condition: Fair, (poorly encapsulated)
  - Plan Showing Location, Size & Height of Ceiling Beams, 7922 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 17, Item 8)
    County Number: 7922
    Size: 31 1/4 x 42 3/4
    Architect's No.: 6
  - Diagram Showing Construction of Roof, 7923 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 1)
    County Number: 7923
    Size: 43 1/4 x 31 1/4
    Architect's No.: 7
  - Elevation of Court House -- Grant Street Front, 7924 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 2)
    County Number: 7924
    Size: 38 1/2 x 43
    Architect's No.: 8
    Condition: Fair, (torn through and taped, older tape at top)
  - Elevation of Courthouse -- Diamond Street Front, 7925 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 3)
    County Number: 7925
    Media: Black & sepia ink on paper
    Size: 47 3/4 x 39
    Architect's No.: 9
    Condition: Poor, (large tears)
  - Elevation of Courthouse -- Fifth Avenue, 7926 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 6)
    County Number: 7926
    Size: 40 x 46 1/2
    Architect's No.: 10
    Condition: Good, not encapsulated
  - Elevation of Courthouse -- Ross Street, 7927 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 4)
    County Number: 7927
    Media: Black ink on linen
    Size: 42 3/4 x 36 3/4
    Architect's No.: 11
    Condition: Fair, (green stains)
  - Elevation of Courtyard, 7928 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 5)
    County Number: 7928
    Description: Courthouse presentation, section through courtyard
    Size: 40 1/4 x 29
    Architect's No.: 12
  - Longitudinal Section of Building Looking Towards Fifth Ave., 7929 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 22, Item 7)
    County Number: 7929
    Size: 39 x 47 1/2
    Architect's No.: 13
    Condition: Fair, not encapsulated
  - Elevation of One-Half Grant Street Front, 7930 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 22, Item 8)
    County Number: 7930
    Scale: 3/8"
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue wash
    Size: 40 1/4 x 49
    Architect's No.: 16
    Condition: Poor, (Torn), not encapsulated
  - Design for Courthouse of Allegheny County, 7931 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 6)
    County Number: 7931
    Description: Courthouse perspective presentation drawing
    Media: Sepia ink on stiff paper, color wash
    Size: 39 x 42 1/2
  - Basement Plan for Jail, 7932 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 7)
    County Number: 7932
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue & red wash
    Size: 33 x 34
    Stamped: E.E. Myers, Architect, Detroit, Mich.
    Architect's No.: 19
  - First Story Plan, 7933 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 18, Item 8)
    County Number: 7933
    Architect's No.: 20
  - Second Story Plan, 7934 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 1)
    County Number: 7934
    Architect's No.: 21
  - Plan of Jail, 7935 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 2)
    County Number: 7935
    Description: Jail presentation roof plan, with diagrams of gables
    Architect's No.: 22
  - Design of Jail and Jailer's Residence, 7936 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 3)
    County Number: 7936
    Description: Jail presentation, perspective rendering
    Media: Full-color rendering on stiff paper
    Size: 47 x 39 3/4
    Condition: Fair, (torn through, taped)
  - Front Elevation towards Grant Street, 7937 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 4)
    County Number: 7937
    Architect: John Ord
    Media: Black ink on paper, red dimensions, color wash
    Size: 48 x 36 1/4
    Condition: Excellent
  - Elevation towards Fifth Avenue, 7938 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 5)
    County Number: 7938
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, color wash
  - Longitudinal Section on Line C-D, 7939 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 6)
    County Number: 7939
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red dimensions, color wash
    Condition: Good, (taped at top)
  - Transverse Section, 7940 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 7)
    County Number: 7940
  - Basement Plan, 7941 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 19, Item 8)
    County Number: 7941
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, blue ink, color wash
    Stamped: John Ord, Architect, Philadelphia
  - First Floor Plan, 7942 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 1)
    County Number: 7942
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red & blue ink, color wash
  - Second Floor Plan, 7943 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 2)
    County Number: 7943
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red & blue ink, sepia wash
  - Second Floor Mezzanine, 7944 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 3)
    County Number: 7944
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, blue ink, sepia wash
  - Third Floor Plan, 7945 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 4)
    County Number: 7945
  - Plan of Pavilion Roofs, 7946 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 5)
    County Number: 7946
    Description: Courthouse presentation drawing, shows Jury Rooms
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, blue & yellow wash
  - Proposed New Jail, 7947 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 20, Item 6)
    County Number: 7947
    Description: Jail presentation elevations
    Size: 36 x 37 3/4
  - Sections and Plans, 7948 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 21, Item 1)
    County Number: 7948
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red dimensions
    Size: 36 x 38
  - Basement Plan, 7949 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 21, Item 2)
    County Number: 7949
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, blue wash
  - Ground Plan, 7950 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 21, Item 3)
    County Number: 7950
    Media: Black ink on stiff paper, red, blue & yellow wash
  - Second Story Plan, 7951 (Map-case 6-5, Folder 21, Item 4)
    County Number: 7951
  - First Story Mezzanine Plan (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 1)
    County Number: Not Available
    Architect: H.H. Richardson
    Size: 51 1/2 x 41
  - Longitudinal Section Through Courthouse and Jail (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 2)
    Media: Sepia ink on paper
    Size: 48 x 85 3/4
  - Diamond Street Elevation (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 3)
    Description: Courthouse & Jail presentation drawing, Forbes elevation
    Size: 48 x 86
    Condition: Excellent, paper torn
  - Ross Street Elevation (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 4)
    Size: 39 1/2 x 50
  - Basement Plan (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 5)
    Size: 44 1/2 x 90
  - Third Story Plan (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 23, Item 6)
    Size: 41 x 51 1/2
- H.H. Richardson's working plans for the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail, II.
  The working drawing is the means by which the architect commits to paper the specifications for the building design and construction. This collection of Richardson's working drawings for the Allegheny County Courthouse project represents the means used to communicate the architectural and engineering design of a monumental construction project that completed itself in the built work of architecture. Beyond the physically practical aspects of these drawings, it is possible to read and interpret each architectural working drawing as a record of Richardson's inspirational seed.
  Harvard University's Houghton Library holds within their H.H. Richardson archival collection design drawings for the Allegheny Courthouse and Jail, but it is important to stress that our collection contains the drawings Richardson submitted to Allegheny County and that were used to construct the buildings.
  - First Floor Mezzanine NW, 10B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 1)
    County Number: 10B
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan
    Media: Black ink on linen, with red dimensions & color wash
    Size: 37 x 46 1/2
    Stamped: Office of H.H. Richardson, Pittsburgh, PA.
    Condition: Poor
  - Plan: First Floor Mezzanine SW, 11B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 2)
    County Number: 11B
    Description: Courthouse working drawing
    Media: Black ink on linen, with red & blue dimension
    Size: 37 x 45
    Condition: Poor (torn at top)
  - Plan: First Floor Mezzanine NE, 12B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 3)
    County Number: 12B
    Size: 37 1/2 x 53
  - Plan: First Floor Mezzanine SE, 13B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 4)
    County Number: 13B
    Size: 36 1/4 x 47 3/4
  - Plan: Second Floor NW, 14B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 5)
    County Number: 14B
    Media: Black ink on linen, with red & blue dimensions and color wash
    Size: 35 1/4 x 46
  - Plan: Second Floor SW, 15B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 1, Item 6)
    County Number: 15B
    Media: Black ink on linen, with red & blue dimensions
    Size: 33 3/4 x 47
    Condition: Poor (missing corners)
  - Second Floor NE, 16B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 1)
    County Number: 16B
    Size: 33 1/2 x 45 1/2
    Condition: Poor (missing top right section)
  - Plan: Second Floor SE, 17B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 2)
    County Number: 17B
    Size: 35 1/2 x 45
  - Second Floor Mezzanine NW, 18 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 3)
    County Number: 18
    Size: 34 3/4 x 49 3/4
    Stamped: Office of H.H. Richardson Pittsburgh, PA.
    Condition: Poor (torn corner)
  - Second Floor Mezzanine SW, 19B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 4)
    County Number: 19B
    Size: 33 1/2 x 49 1/2
  - Second Floor Mezzanine NE, 20B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 5)
    County Number: 20B
    Media: Black ink on linen, with red & blue dimensions & color wash
    Size: 34 1/2 x 50 1/2
  - Second Floor Mezzanine SE, 21B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 6)
    County Number: 21B
    Size: 35 x 49
  - Third Floor Plan NW, 22A (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 7)
    County Number: 22A
    Size: 33 3/4 x 48 1/2
    Condition: Very Bad (missing corner, waxy stain)
  - Third Floor Plan NW, 22B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 2, Item 8)
    County Number: 22B
    Size: 37" x 47"
    Condition: Bad (missing title)
  - Third Floor Plan SW, 23A (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 1)
    County Number: 23A
    Size: 34 x 44
    Condition: Very Bad (missing large section on bottom; orange wax-like substance stuck to drawing)
  - Third Floor Plan SW, 23B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 2)
    County Number: 23B
    Size: 50 1/2 x 36
    Condition: Poor (torn missing edges)
  - Third Floor Plan NE, 24A (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 3)
    County Number: 24A
    Size: 33 1/2 x 49 1/4
    Condition: Poor (stained, torn corners, creases)
  - Third Floor Plan NE, 24B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 4)
    County Number: 24B
    Size: 36 x 46
    Condition: Poor (torn edges)
  - Third Floor SE, 25A (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 5)
    County Number: 25A
    Size: 34 1/2 x 48 1/2
    Condition: Bad (corners torn & missing, stains, taped)
  - Third Floor SE, 25B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 3, Item 6)
    County Number: 25B
    Size: 36 x 49
    Condition: Bad (hole in middle)
  - Section on Line EF, 34B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 1)
    County Number: 34B
    Size: 32 x 57 1/2
    Condition: Very Bad (torn, missing large sections)